Raycasting is the process of shooting
Raycast とはある地点から透明な線 (Ray) を
an invisible ray from a point, in a
特定の方向に引いて
specified direction to detect whether any
その Ray 上のどこかでコライダがあるか
colliders lay in the path of the ray.
検知するものです。
One such example of this would be
例をあげると、
shooting a gun. In this instance our
銃から弾を発射するケースです。このレッスンでは
character wants to shoot the evil box that
キャラクターが、
betrayed him and killed his father.
裏切り者で父を殺した敵である悪魔の箱を撃つことにしましょう。
The syntax of the raycast function looks like this.
Raycast 関数の文法は次のようなものです。
It can be confusing at first
最初はまぎわらしいかもしれませんが
but once you understand what each part does
一回それぞれの部分で何がおこなわれるのか
it makes much more sense.
理解すれば良く意味が分かるようになります。
Firstly, the origin of the ray is a
最初に Ray の原点は
point in world space.
ワールド空間座標のどこかの地点です。
So in this instance we'd choose a point in
このレッスンでは銃の銃口の前の地点を
front of the barrel of the gun, stored
どこか選んで
as a Vector3, an X, Y and Z position.
Vector3 として X, Y, Z を格納します。
However, because our world coordinates
しかし、ワールド空間座標の向きは
direction won't be facing in the direction
撃つ方向に向いていないため
we're shooting we will need a second Vector3
二つめの Vector3 により向き(direction) を
to store our direction in.
格納する必要があります。
These two Vector3 variables make up
この二つの Vector3 変数により
our ray. But we can also substitute
Ray が構成されます。さらに Ray 変数により
in a Ray variable, as this data type
代用が可能であり、このデータ型で
can store two Vector3's.
二つの Vector3 変数を格納出来ます。
Our code would then look like this.
コードは次のようになります。
The next argument in the function is a
関数の次の引数は
RaycastHit variable that stores
RaycastHit 変数であり、
information on the colliders hit.
コライダの衝突にもとづいて情報を格納します。
So that it can be queried in code as to which
これにより、コードの中でクエリをかけて
objects are intersected by the ray.
どのオブジェクトが Ray と交差するか判定出来ます。
Finally there are two optional arguments,
最後に、必須ではない引数が二つあります。
Distance, which defines the length
ひとつは Distance であり Ray の長さが決まり、
of the ray, if omitted the ray will default
もし省略した場合、 Ray の長さはデフォルトで
to an infinite length.
無限（infinity）となります。
And Layer Mask. This is the number
そしてレイヤーマスク（Layer Mask）です。これは
of a particular layer in Unity's layer system
Unity のレイヤーシステムにおける特定のレイヤー番号であり、
on which you can place objects if you
もし Ray に無視させたいオブジェクトがある場合、
wish to make the ray ignore them.
そのレイヤーに配置することができます。
Let's look at another practical example of
それでは Raycast を使用した実用的な例を
using raycasting.
みていきます。
In this example we have a parachute crate
このサンプルではパラシュートつきの壷があり
that opens a parachute when it's
フロアに近いとき、パラシュートが
nearing the floor.
開きます。
The crate is made up of two parts,
壷は二つの部分から構成されていて
the chute and the crate itself.
パラシュートと壷そのものです。
The chute has two animations
パラシュートには二つのアニメーションがあり、
one to open the chute
一つはパラシュートを開くためののものであり、
and another to close it.
もうひとつは閉じるためのものです。
In this example we need to cast a ray
このサンプルでは Raycast を下方向に
downwards in order to see how far the crate is
行なってフロアから壷がどれくらい
from the floor, and we check for the
離れているかみて、environment コライダを
floor by looking for the environment collider.
みつけることでフロアの確認を行ないます。
Our collider for the environment is tagged
environment コライダは
with the word environment.
environment という用語でタグづけされています。
And in our script we are looking for that tag.
スクリプトの中でそのタグを探しています。
The RayCast function gets placed inside
Raycast 関数は if 文の中に
an IF statement so that if it returns true,
配置されているので、もし戻り値が true である場合、
meaning if it intersects with anything,
つまり何かと交差した場合、
then the comments within the IF statement
if 文の中のコマンドが実行されて
will be carried out and the RayCastHit
RaycastHit 変数にクエリをかけて
variable can be queried as to what has been hit.
何をヒットしたかが取得できます。
So within an IF statement we've written
今回 if 文の中に
Physics.Raycast, we have a landingRay variable
Physics.Raycast を記述して、landingRay 変数により
that's storing the position of the box
箱の位置および下向きの方向を
and a downward direction. We're using
格納します。Vector3.down というショートカット
the shortcut Vector3.down,
を今回使用しています。
and we're using this as the ray to cast.
そしてこれを Raycast で使用する Ray としています。
Our RaycastHit variable - 'hit' -
RaycastHit 変数である hit は
is storing anything that gets hit by the
下向きに Raycast するときに、
ray as it is cast downwards,
Ray によりヒットを受けるもの全てを格納します。
and the distance, or 'length' or the ray
そして Ray の距離、すなわち length は
is defined by our 'deployment height' variable.
deploymentHeight 変数により定義されます。
If the ray intersects with a collider
もし Ray がコライダと交差した場合、
then we call the deploy parachute function.
DeployParachute 関数をコールします。
This function then simply sets our Boolean
この関数は boolean 型である deployed フラグに true くをセットして
'deployed' flag to true so that this cannot repeat.
反復しないようにします。
And then we set the drag of the rigid body
次に Rigidbody の Drag を
to the variable 'parachuteEffectiveness'.
に parachuteEffectiveness 変数の値をセットします。
So we slow down the crate as if it's being
このため 壷がパラシュートにより抑制されたかのように
held up by the parachute.
動きを遅くします。
We also play the animation
さらに parachute オブジェクトのアニメーションを
on the parachute object,
再生して、
which is a game object that we'll assign
これは public 変数に割り当てする
to the public variable.
ゲームオブジェクトです。
We then have a separate OnCollisionEnter function
次に別の OnCollisionEnter  があり、
which simply plays the closing animation.
閉じるアニメーションを再生します。
So we know that as soon as it hits the ground
このため、地面または別のオブジェクトに当たると、パラシュートは
or another object the parachute can close.
閉じることが出来ます。
So here we've set the length of the ray to 4
ここで Ray の length に 4 をセットするために
by setting 4 as our deployment height
deplomentHeight に 4 をセットします。
And we're setting the drag of the rigidbody to 8
Rigidbody の Drag に 8 をセットするために
by setting the parachute effectiveness to 8.
Parachute Effectiveness に 8 をセットします。
And we've simply dragged our parachute
そして prop_parachuteCrate_chute オブジェクト を
chute object on to the parachute variable.
Parachute 変数の上にドラッグしています。
Because this is the object that has an animation
Animation コンポーネントがアタッチされているオブジェクトである
component in order to playback
ため、開いたり閉じたりするアンメーションを
it's opening and closing animations.
再生するためです。
So let's see that play one more time.
それでは再生をもう一回だけみてみましょう。
It's also worth keeping in mind
シーンビューまたはゲームビューで
that although you cannot see
Raycast が描画されないことは
raycasts drawn in the scene view
覚えておくべき
or in the game. You can also use the
です。一方で
Debug.DrawRay function
Debug.DrawRay 関数を使用すれば
in order to preview where a ray would be going.
Ray のプレビューをすることが出来ます。
By adding Debug.DrawRay
Debug.DrawRay を追加することで
we're drawing a visual ray from
Vector3.down の向きに
the position of the box in the direction
箱の位置からの
of Vector3.down, multiplied by
視覚的な Ray を描画して、
the deployment height - the length of our existing ray.
長さとしては length に deploymentHeight を掛け算することが出来ます。
And by doing this we've matched the actual
こうすることで、
ray that we're casting in the IF statement below.
下の if 文で実際に行なう Raycast と一致します。
So when we play this back you can see that
再生を行なうことで、
Unity demonstrates the ray
Unity 上のシーンビューにて Ray が
by showing us the drawn ray in the scene view.
描画されるところを確認することができます。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)